so reach we reach the ACI teacher
training class 8 of course 1 and we're
going to talk about we already talked
about the benefits of bodhichitta how
cool is bodhichitta we talked about nine
different things and then we talked
about 22 different things and then
you're supposed to be hungry for it no
you're supposed to say oh gosh la that
sounds good to me
i'll buy this car how much is this car
what do I have to pay then there are
seven steps how do you say 7 like that
in China 7 know it with a hand Oh
7 6 7 8 ok alright I like it
you can talk secret to your friends no
okay so seven steps seven and a half
okay seven and a half steps to get
bodhichitta yourself okay there's two
famous methods one is exchanging
yourself and others okay starts with
that doctrine about - and JAMA
- steps really seeing that we are all
equal we all have equal right to
happiness and then exchanging yourself
with other people seeing what do they
want in English what's the idiom yeah
put yourself in the other person's shoes
right so there's two great traditions
for developing bodhichitta so that's one
you think about
we all equal we all have equal right to
happiness and the second part of that is
you exchange other people I didn't put
it in the homework because it's
depressing because you're supposed to
put yourself in other people's in your
friends shoes and then you're supposed
to look at Michael
so I put myself in I don't know Jeff's
shoes and he's looking at Michael and
he's thinking why didn't he tell me like
yesterday you know we're gonna do a song
together
why didn't he you know we've been here a
week and he couldn't think ahead and let
me know this is so nervous to prepare in
one hour and anyway it doesn't have a
good guitar here for me and Marcus is
thinking I guess I was ever gonna play
it but then he didn't talk to me for
three days so it's kind of depressing
the real exchanging self and others it's
not very fun you you try to imagine how
other people see you especially when
you're not very considerate okay so I
didn't put in the homework because it's
too sad okay so we're gonna do the
seven-step say agin day may not
do-gooding day may not done game day
means mr. human dictionary who took all
my money
you notice I didn't bet you for a few
days I'm out of money any cause and
effect may not do seven advices for
cause and effect okay you get the first
one it causes the second one you get the
SEC when I went cousins there it's like
the Wheel of Life but a good one okay
it's a good Wheel of Life
so I'll give you their famous names okay
say Marche 10 10 10 saw your own jumper
ninja temple lot some non that and then
chant you kiss him okay so we're gonna
go through these seven tonight if we
have time which Tim hopes I do will do
part of class in fact we have to do
class nine tonight this so yeah cuz
tomorrow's a little tight also I
promised you a bees in the birds lecture
but I'm gonna wait till the last day so
you don't leave because you want to hear
about it in America your parents are
supposed to give you this talk about how
where babies come from and some parents
some dads are too shy and they never
explain it to the kid and the kid thinks
the baby comes from bird store so it's a
part of my job to educate you in
everything okay all right first one
marche means if you came into this life
with a mind okay if you had a first
thought in this mind then according to
buddhism it must come from a you tungee
cause it must come from her same stuff
and in buddhism we say mind and body are
separate minded body are connected if
you drink a lot of alcohol your mind
will get stupid if you have a lot of
pressure at work with your mind you will
get ulcer you'll get a heart attack so
there's a connection but they are
different stuff so if you have a with
this is a ACI course for proof of future
life - proof of past life if you had a
first thought in this life then you must
have had a thought before because
nothing comes from nothing
they never could there's a song you have
to learn okay
nothing comes from nothing so somewhere
in my youth for a childhood I must have
done some thing good okay it's a anyway
I love this song
from my parents generation hundred years
ago and so nothing comes from nothing
and if you have a first thought in this
life it must have come from I thought
before okay
which means you how to previous life
which means you had a mother in that
life okay normally you had a mother and
if you had one previous life then it
doesn't make sense that you would have
less than countless previous lives which
came first chicken or the egg what's the
Buddhist answer that's correct
there's no faith you can't take egg came
first you can't say chicken came first
and you know when kids you tell each
other this question they think they're
very smart they think they're very cute
the other person's like but actually
it's a good question and the answer is
obvious there was no first egg and there
was no first chicken okay that can't be
that's a rough example but if you take a
single moment of consciousness there
can't be nothing before that and there
can't be something that's completely
different like iron or oxygen there
there has to be awareness makes
awareness so you have had countless
knives you have had countless mothers
and even if there are countless living
beings in the universe which we say
there are in Buddhism we say there are
countless living beings you can see all
of them
in this life okay you can do it just try
okay try hard it's the sweetest thing in
this life okay almost try and then you
will see directly then you don't need me
to teach you you will see directly that
there are countless living beings in
this universe and statistically each one
has been your mom okay how many times
yeah like countless times
okay then when you TJC i okay especially
in the United States you will get some
strange questions you know like I don't
like my mom I hate my mom you know and I
don't care of somebody with my mom if
they were my mom I hate them more okay
and only an American will ask this
question I don't know why even if you
don't like your mom even if you don't
get along even if she wasn't a good mom
even if she threw you out two days after
you were born she carried you for nine
months and these days you can get an
abortion you don't have to have a kid
but your mom decided to have a kid you
see and she risk her life to give you
life it was a tread 50-50 you know if
you die to give life to this child will
you give it and your mom said yes I will
die and I will give my life to this one
you know so we're all amazing lucky you
know I saw a birth I went to see Lama or
his birth of her baby me and Veronica
went into Sun I think it took
two-and-a-half or three days of labor we
were the last people who didn't leave we
finally left to tell you the truth and
then I thought who will go through this
for another person
it's unbelievable I can't imagine it you
know so whatever you think of your mom
she gave you your life and normally she
taught you how to talk I remember my mom
teaching me words you know and I would
say like banana banana and she'd say no
banana
I said B'Elanna and she said no banana
and I said banana and then she'd be so
happy she you can have some candy and
that's why I learned a lot of Scripture
so she taught you to walk and the first
I don't know four or five years you're
extremely vulnerable you can die from
anything if your mom leave you alone a
dog can come in and kill you by accident
anything can happen you can get sick in
India 60,000 kids go missing every year
they are stolen for sex trade and things
like that
so if your mother doesn't watch you all
the time think about you all the time
then you die you know so you know
appreciate what is a mom and that's the
second step of the seven sage in ten
yeah think about how nice she was some
kind she was feed you from her own body
I heard this in the pub uncle in
Virginia in the scripture they say just
after you tore your mother's guts open
she'll pick you up and kiss you a
thousand times like you really did
something nice to her yeah wow that's
really strange
and then when Katie had her baby I don't
know me and Adam are kind of close to
each other so he sent me the video of
that moment not just before I said don't
send me that way and she's picking out
the baby for the first
time and she's kissing the baby for the
first time but her breath it's like you
know and she's strong she's very healthy
she's young you know and I'm like wow
and she she wasn't even thinking about
it and the video was kind of scary but
her breath was like someone who almost
died because she did almost die so
second step 10/10 means think of all the
nice things she did for us okay she she
had to feed us three times a day
gentle food I think the coolest thing is
they teach you how to talk and they
teach you how to read they teach you how
to walk okay so when you do this
meditation the first part is just logic
okay it takes mine to create mind there
must have been a previous moment of mine
before the first moment in this life
which is proof that you've been alive
countless lies no beginning and everyone
has been your mother okay everybody in
the universe has been your mother and
statistically countless times not like
once or twice okay everyone spin your
mother okay ten ten now when do you do
this meditation when you drive back to
Tucson you do this meditation you stop
at the truck stop which in America are
rough places okay I'm sorry
it's what many of you are seeing of
America it's there usually some of the
dirtiest places the toilet stopped on
the highway maybe in your country it's
the same in China they're beautiful I'm
sorry but uh so these are rough places
rough people go there and so you go into
a store and oftentimes this rough people
in there people and around here they
walk in the store with guns on you know
they have guns real guns and
and they they mean you know and so I
predict on the way the Tucson if you
stop for peepee if you have strong
bladder you don't have to stop but if
you stop in one of these rough places
you will see some I think you might see
some rough people okay and if you're
like me okay I'm a Buddhist
I just started I'm a Buddhist so I'm
supposed to be nice to everybody I'm
supposed to treat everybody equal but
when I see them I kind of avoid them you
know like I go down this aisle and I
come back to get the cherry pie so I
don't like to walk past them you know I
feel actually I think I feel a little
bit scared or something I don't want to
meet them you know and then I decide
there are rough person there a dirty
person maybe dangerous person okay so
starting tomorrow if you're going back
to the airport tomorrow when you stop at
these gas stations in Arizona it's a
poor state in there a little bit rough
places and maybe you will see one of
these people then I challenge you to do
your marche meditation in tension first
two steps okay like stop your reaction
you know this is a rough person and say
this rough person has been my mom this
rough person gave me milk from their
breast even if it's a man right it's a
little strange you see a rough guy and
he's all like and then it's kind of a
stranger it's a cool strange thing
stopping the store look at them and say
this this is my mom I lost my mom and I
found her again and she said this is the
mom who gave me milk
for years you know this is the mom who
risk her life for me and there's a
special magic that comes from these two
steps okay
and you should experience it it's very
very cool I used to do it on the subway
in New York subway in New York is very
dangerous in those times but they get
better Nancy oh no not much better I
mean in the old days you never say
anything to anybody you avoid anyone who
looks dangerous and right especially at
night and sorry I remembered I had to go
on the subway every day and in New York
you face the other people in many of the
chairs you face the other people and you
try not to look at them there's a
unspoken rule in New York that you don't
look in someone's eyes unless you want
to fight say keep your eyes down you
know and then I would be doing this
meditation you know and here to be this
big rough mean-looking businessmen and I
think oh he opened his shirt and gave me
milk you know thank you
you know and and something happens in
the subway car some sweet feeling starts
to change in the subway car okay and you
will really enjoy it okay or in the
store on the way to Tucson okay the
little gasoline store it's a wonderful
way to live your life
okay this meditation is magic okay and
you can do the what he called to
husband's in the kitchen thing
oh this disgusting person's coming for
me I must have been disgusting but this
one is sweeter you know this one is like
you're so disgusting and you gave me
milk
you know and the whole feeling in the
store changes everyone feels it in the
subway or on the airplane
some kind of body languages you're like
you know and everybody's like say
everyone senses it from body language
and the whole mood in the airplane
changes everyone changes so especially
if you're in a frightening situation
when the dog barks when the bee stings
when I'm feeling sad okay like when
you're in a tough situation the American
passport guys giving you a hassle are
you sure are you sure what you're doing
and then you've got to be he gave me
milk then he'll be okay go ahead when
you're afraid they smell it and they
they want to be more tough but just
remember the milk okay and something
magic happens okay so do it okay do it
it makes your life very magical you
don't have to do it all day okay it gets
a little indigestion if you have
narcotic just once or twice when you're
afraid or someone's being tough to you
or you know you're a little bit
uncomfortable with somebody then just I
wonder if it was sweet or salty you know
and the whole atmosphere changes okay
it's a magic it's a magic pill it's like
eating with a guy that movie matrix it's
a good matrix pill okay everything
changes in the whole room okay just try
it and Buddhism should be fun if you're
not having fun and Buddhism you're doing
it wrong okay something's wrong if
you're very serious you're not a good
Buddhist okay Buddhists are silly and
they play happy song
okay and you should pull out this pill
and take it okay when you're tense or
someone's yelling at you you can say
yeah but thanks for the melon I hate you
but the milk is a good thing okay so
that's called 1010 okay 1010 third step
10 sauce a chainsaw if this person gave
me milk countless times and if they risk
their life to give me life at least I
should be nice to them
okay at least I should show some
gratitude that's number three okay chin
saw means to pay back the gratitude to
pay back the kindness I'm a person so do
something I'm give them a smile in some
places in America if you smile they also
hit you you can smile small smile and
just imagine I would like to pay you
back you know I'm grateful you risked
your life for me so there's nobody you
ever mean animal bird human there's
nobody you ever mean that you shouldn't
be nice to them because they they all
gave you your life okay they all gave
you life I'm gonna tell you another
stupid American idea okay I'm sorry to
pick on America but picking on America
is an American tradition so actually I'm
being patriotic many many people will
say well I don't see why I should why
should I pay them back me that was a
long time ago if your theory is correct
dinner they also killed me countless
Turks they threw me in the fire
countless times they shot me with a gun
countless times you're not looking at
the whole picture
you know yeah they gave me birth
countless times but they also killed me
countless times they killed my family
countless times they destroyed my
country countless times you know then I
call that just bad attitude okay and
part of my enjoying teaching you these
courses twenty-seven years later is I
have these 66 understandings me and John
we have proof of high realization
Sakia Bank Asia monopoly I forget is
sitting duck there's a one sakiyama
who's famous even in our tradition I
think he's mentioned in this book first
for for formalizing the training of a
spiritual partner so he's fake poppin
crumpyj says if you want to know about
spiritual partners go study his books
and whenever they paid him he's bald
like me and John and then when you ask
the lamas you know why is he bald
they say intense realizations intense
realization the heat is rising in
burning off the hair okay so you can
check it out
I think it's Sonam don't mean the psycho
koma koma koma me not burn it
I'll check okay anyway so in your life
from 66 right John you're 67 right okay
you have a choice okay
there's crappy stuff in life and there's
sweet stuff in life and I don't care how
advanced you are if you came to this
gamma come a doctor if you came to this
okay you have about 50% crap and sweet
things it's 5050 if you're mother Teresa
you have 51 and 49 okay seriously none
of us is so much better than anyone else
in this world okay we all have the same
six main negative emotions we all have
the same mistakes we all did the same
bad things okay or we wouldn't be here
okay so your life is a carnival and a
cannon debe black and white mix 50/50
karma so cool um uh Kirsten organist
rhythm iteration yoga Sutra fourth
chapter your life is mixed okay
fifty-fifty half of the things are gonna
be sin and half of the things are going
to be beautiful so you have a choice
okay you can focus on the sad things or
you can focus on the happy things and
really you have a choice okay you have a
choice you can go to the gasoline store
and the first guy you say you see this
guy killed me countless times this guy
killed me countless times in my past
night okay that's true but what a
miserable life you know what a miserable
way to live okay
oh this guy hurt me in high school he
was my booth you know it's true okay
nobody said it's not true it's true and
many people hurt you in your life but
you have a choice right you always have
a choice you know you can look at the
dark side or you look at the sunny side
okay so that's my answer to that debate
when someone says when you're teaching
these seven steps some irritating
student and it's usually the same one
coming from you and they will say yeah
but this guy killed me countless times
and you can say that's true but do you
want to spend your whole life looking at
people who killed you or would you
rather have some magic
in the store you see would you rather
have some fun in your life and really
life is so difficult for everybody don't
waste your time to be honest I've been
criticized by about everybody and just
let it go okay it doesn't help you it
doesn't make you happy it doesn't
improve it just said you know you
criticize me yeah I know there's dumb
people in the world and it's okay you
know
don't focus on it okay people who give
you trouble I'm telling you from 66 on
67 Red John don't focus on those people
say I appreciate you criticize me by the
way
in English we say a grain of truth right
almost all criticism has at least 1%
true okay so if you're a really good
person
listen to the criticism take the 1% and
let go of the 99%
okay I'm not I appreciate your comment
you know I appreciate what you said I'll
work on it
but the rest is [__] and I'm not
gonna spend my time I'm not gonna worry
about it when I get home I'm gonna have
a nice dinner
I'm gonna watch Netflix and then I'm
gonna read diamond cutter Sutra or maybe
the Sutra first in case I die okay so
don't don't take seriously okay don't
don't spend your life worrying about
what somebody said about you there's a
grain of truth fix something but don't
look at bad things don't go around your
whole life saying this person killed me
and countless lifetimes okay you're just
wasting your time okay and you don't
have time and life is full of
unbelievably beautiful things okay if
you just look at the poopoo and not the
beautiful things then then you're some
kind of crazy person okay there's so
many beautiful things okay then focus on
them okay
that's my non emptiness Dharma
advice okay focus on the nice things
okay so step number three tinsel you
should say I want to pay this mom back
you know I owe you thanks for the milk
can I pay for your hostess cupcakes in
the store you know I mean we have a cool
custom I really think a CAI teacher
should do it once a month or something
it's very very fun okay we go to
restaurant we did it with jasmine
jasmine and Tim we went for a meeting in
the town here and we went to the only
restaurant which was open for only one
day your honor and we had dinner and
there was a big Mexican family next to
us three four generations and they were
very beautiful you know they're all
Cowboys and you could see they had a
hard life and and but they were having
fun with each other they were really
loving each other and so if you're want
to do this step three
repay their kindness ask for their bill
as for their bill and then pay it
secretly and leave before they ask the
waiter and waitress not to tell them
until you leave you know sometimes it's
cool to watch in the window and they're
like and they're like I think sometimes
the waiter keeps the money
but nah I don't think so
they also like the game okay so it's a
beautiful practice okay this is my own
it's not in the lung room okay maybe it
is I didn't find it yeah you know pick
up their check pay their bill sight
quietly secretly Scott no II went to LA
for breakfast I mean they never ever
take a break and they told there's one
Israeli breakfast place so they went
there there's none in Arizona forget it
and so they weren't there but tonight
the night before they went to a
restaurant in and they said we're gonna
pay that couples bill because they look
unhappy with each other the husband's
not talking to the wife the whites not
talking to the husband that's a really
good one to pay the bill
if they spend the whole time on the
phone and they don't look at each other
it means their marriage got unhappy and
they need some I guess that's gonna take
a rest
okay here we go relax
oh yeah Scottie Reid said well pay that
couples bill and then the the waitress
brought him a bill for $3,000 it was a
big test of their Buddhism because they
ordered a very expensive bottle of wine
like a $2,000 bottle of wine but they
they kept their bloody titter and
they've paid the bill
okay it's like two credit cards so do
little things to honor your mom okay
dude little things it's really really
fun if you're having a bad day someone
yelled at you or something didn't go
right do these practices okay in your
mindset thanks for the milk mom and then
I don't know pay for their bill okay
there's an ice cream store in Japan I
think some person gave extra money and
they said I'm paying for the next person
please tell the next person it's free
and I think 700 people in a row did it
and that's really cool okay play play
little mom honoring games okay it's not
stupid it'll plant deep seeds I think
it's better than meditating on I know
this was my mom you know paying a three
thousand dollar wine bill is this that's
devotion okay all right step number four
se-yeon Champa it's called my tree my
tree in Sanskrit it's where my trades
name comes from and it means love okay
and these next two steps step number
four is called love and step number five
is called compassion okay great
compassion so step number four is called
love
and it's a special kind of love where
you enjoy staring at your kid you know
you're like this okay you know when
you're in love with your girlfriend in
high school you like did you do this
thing with your girlfriend or boyfriend
in high school you just look at each
other's eyes for one hour and you know I
mean it wears off but you on jump on
means love that loves the way this
person looks okay so when you see this
rough person in the gasoline store or
you see this couple who's having a fight
in the restaurant then just look at them
and give them love now this kind of
number four and number five are
different okay number four wants to give
the person beautiful things okay the
definition of love
the definition of love in the seven
steps is I want to give beautiful things
to this person okay like I want this
person to have a bike and I want this
person to have candy and I want this
person to have a good salary and I want
this person to have a beautiful
boyfriend all right okay so you look at
people and you wish them good things
okay that's called young jumper your own
means attractive love attractive my tree
it means you look at them and you have a
crush on them in English it means
you know you know when I met Veronica uh
50 years ago okay this year uh okay so
uh like that but for everybody okay
they're like your child okay then the
next one is named HMO maja Karuna
compassion and in Buddhism
Karuna is different from my tree my tree
wants to give nice things
Karuna wants to take away problems okay
Karuna wants to take away problem okay
$400 except for a word who never forgets
anything strange guy
which comes first
wait I want logic too I mean the 100
bucks is 100 bucks I want a good answer
I don't want a sucky answer compared to
a kid who fell off their bike explain
what the boob wound
yeah good okay good yeah see there's a
big debate about these two steps in
Buddhism people say compassion should
come first because you don't give a kid
candy if they are crying because they
hurt their leg you know first you fix
the leg you kiss that don't like who got
it right was it guilty man okay shopping
hundred bucks for the boss okay yeah
first you take care of their trouble and
then you give them something sweet okay
first you take care of their trouble
then you give so some llamas teach it
the other way okay you can do it either
way
is there some argument you can think of
for $0 why love should come first
okay that's a pretty good argument if
you don't care about them why would you
want to take away their pain so that's
good that's actually the classical
answer all right
I got out of that cheap what number we
on number six okay say schlock some numb
doc this is one of my favorite ideas in
Buddhism mmm it means I take
responsibility the American President
Truman had a sign on his desk that said
the Box stops here it means I'm the last
step in the respond
I accept responsibility for this whole
country for everybody I will make final
decisions you know and Bodhisattvas are
like that okay so now there's an
important ACI teacher training thing
here okay and you better have lots of
numbers or you will never be a Dharma
teacher okay
you better have number 6 or you will
never be a Dharma teacher I take
responsibility for the program I will
find the place I will get the readings
together I'll pay for everything I will
get refreshments ready for everybody and
I don't care if nobody helps me okay I'm
on my own I accept that
it's my honor to take final
responsibility okay the buck stops here
the responsibility stops here and I
accept it I know it's gonna come I know
there's gonna be hard days when no one
helps you we used to have special
ceremonies choice a month called sage a
tantric ceremony in in our teachers
house and I don't know 20 students would
come and me and geshe-la thought we
hated those ceremonies because the
Buddhist people make the biggest mess of
any kind of people I don't know what it
is
you give refreshments to a Buddhist it's
all over the floor maybe they're
thinking equanimity for ants or some I
don't know what it is but good Buddhists
ACI Dharma students studying compassion
and bodhichitta they make the biggest
messes lock the door to the toilet if
you don't want to clean it for two hours
somehow the Buddhist boy can't hit the
target in the toilet I don't know what
it is maybe it's some kind of compassion
but we would spend at least two hours
cleaning up after them two people
working hard it would take us two hours
to clean after them so don't expect help
don't expect support don't expect
encouragement don't expect thank you
just expect hard work okay and it's your
honor
okay and you're lucky to be a ACI
teacher and that's called socks I'm them
done and if you don't have it you will
never help the universe okay cuz you're
gonna get the minute you stick your head
up all the demons come okay it's a
famous Buddhist saying you raise your
head up all the troubles gonna come to
you okay so if you want the demons to
leave you alone watch YouTube your whole
life or Netflix never do any Dharma okay
but if you decide to be an ACI teacher
be tough okay and no one's going to help
you if you were going to wait for people
to help you you will never be a CI
teacher okay you pay you find the place
you get the readings ready you deal with
the two or three really crazy students
okay and that's your life for the rest
of your life okay
and it's the sweetest life you can have
I think John and I and Connie we've been
doing this Dharma business for 50 years
and it's a great business okay Dharma
teaching is the happiest thing you can
do in your life but don't expect him
okay and if you don't get help
just enjoy okay I love cleaning the
floor of the sacred cave that was
offered in the puja you know and rubbed
into the carpet by a bodhisattva
you know I'm so honored you know you got
it things like that okay right
underneath it she takes care of me yeah
okay okay so that's number six and you
know even if you give up a CI in if you
give up Buddhism even if you decide to
do something else in your life this
attitude is really sweet
okay I take responsibility for
everything I'll fundraise
you know I'll buy the cakes you know if
you want to lose money be an ACI teacher
okay by the way it turns around later I
can tell you that okay
right Velma then people start giving you
money but it's not the first day or the
or the or the third or fourth year okay
takes time for karma to ripen but anyway
it doesn't matter
I take responsibility I'm I will do it
and you have to have this if you're
gonna be a teacher and it's a beautiful
feeling it's a really beautiful feeling
you are the mom of the family called all
living beings you are the mom of the
family called all living things and moms
moms don't avoid responsibility moms
always take responsibility okay all
right if you have these six you get
number seven for $100 if you have these
things oh yeah it is buddy Jenna okay
but why is it different from the first
six what it's a what $100 from a human
computer
I need to borrow some money there to get
home yeah this is the only one which is
only a result and not a cause I'm sure
it doesn't cause Buddhahood right word
just kidding you know in this list it's
it's one which is only a result so don't
forget the name of the list is the cause
and effect advices but number seven is
only a result okay so if you start
tomorrow
practicing in the gasoline store on the
airplane or in the airport if someone
pushes you with their luggage there's a
special kind of luggage all over the
world that's designed to run over your
feet they give it to old ladies mostly
and if someone we rearranges your foot
with their luggage then you're gonna do
this milk meditation okay like you're
gonna look at them okay and the whole
feeling in the airport will change check
it out it's really fun it's really fun
okay we finished the homework except for
the last question which is I told you
how many steps no I said seven and a
half so here's the half okay here's the
half it's traditional to start the seven
with equanimity okay unless you already
feel equal towards all other people it's
gonna be hard for you to think this was
my mom
you see it's gonna be hard for you to do
step number one unless you already feel
pretty equal all religions all countries
all races men women old young nice mean
if you can't get over that you can't
start the list you're not allowed to
start the list and that's a pretty big
half you know it just means you have to
work on it okay and the way to work on
it you know you're in a line people keep
cutting in the line I went to Kyrgyzstan
at 3 o'clock in the morning Bishkek
Airport there's one customs officer
there were like a thousand passengers
and we stood there for four or five
hours and people fought with each other
it was very traumatic and we had to
catch a plane and so in those hard
moments you have to remember everybody
in this line wants to go you know
everybody in this life wants to have a
happy life everybody wants money
everybody wants a beautiful family you
know everybody wants to be healthy it's
not right to discriminate between people
okay we are taught in America we are
brought up because this country is such
a [__] [__] means mixed up dog mixed
up somebody asked me what country are
your parents from I had no idea you know
in America it's always we're all mixed
up
we don't know what what's our parents
racially where they come from so it
doesn't really you know in this country
you are taught as a child respect every
country respect every race we don't do
it okay I know but at least we the
teachers tell us in the school
everybody's equal you know you should
respect everybody but it's a bigger kind
of equality everybody is equal that they
want to be happy everybody
there's nobody want to be unhappy
somebody told me in a class what about
people commit suicide I think they're
trying to be happy on some they're
trying to stop there
everybody wants to be at we're all equal
okay we all have the same goal we're not
different from each other so so relax
when you're in the airport for four
hours in the lion everyone's pushing in
front of you we have an equal right to
go to go through the line we have equal
right you can't say we don't have equal
right we all have equal right everybody
wants to be happy they're all just
trying to be happy all of us when we try
to be happy we hurt other people by
accident okay we don't think we just try
to get what we want and oftentimes we
hurt other people okay so people are
gonna hurt you sometimes it's okay you
know I was complaining about someone who
hurt me and my mama gave me you seen
this photo there's a photograph of a
young beautiful woman who jumped out of
the highest building in America and she
landed on her car and she died instantly
but the car looks like a beautiful bed
it's all looks like a blanket like a
soft blanket and she's kind of has this
look on her face you know like she
doesn't look like crazy or anything
she's kind of peaceful and she's sitting
on this car that she crushed with her
body in my lama said look if people do
this to themselves why you think they
won't do something to you okay if people
do this kind of pain to themselves many
many people overeat many people smoke
many people drink many people give
themselves cancer give themselves heart
attack 65 percent of people in America
give themselves diabetes overweight if
they can't be nice to themselves why are
you so surprised they're not nice to you
you know it's the human nature you know
we all trying to be happy
we're all trying to get something for us
now so relax okay everyone's equal this
is how to do the first yeah that's the
lady this is how to do the first
meditation okay this is how they if
people hurt themselves then of course
they're gonna hurt you
okay don't be surprised that people who
are trying to get what they want
sometimes they hurt you okay but we're
all equal okay got it
that finishes class ain't right Tim I'm
exactly on schedule if I may say so kind
of kind of exactly on school and we're
gonna go to class 9 okay